<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Otaku View</title>
	<subtitle>Thoughts of the digitally obsessed</subtitle>
	<link href="https://otakuview.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://otakuview.com"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://otakuview.com/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Rainbow Six Siege 2021 Cinematics are Phenomenal</title>
		<published>2021-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://otakuview.com/rainbow-six-siege-2021-cinematics-phenomenal/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://otakuview.com/rainbow-six-siege-2021-cinematics-phenomenal/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;rainbow-six-siege-cinematic-arena.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rainbow Six Siege 2021 Cinematic Arena&quot; title=&quot;Rainbow Six Siege 2021 Cinematic Arena&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&#x27;ve been away Tom Clancy&#x27;s Rainbow Six Siege for over two years due to a combination of low interest and the growingly toxic community, the 2021 cinematics are legitimately amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;div &gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube-nocookie.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;Nf1w1B8jdXE&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why on earth have these cinematics been so poorly advertised? Ubisoft has clearly spent extensive effort on these, but their marketing and advertising team has dropped the ball on sharing them, which is honestly a shame.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Rainbow Six Extraction has been delayed until January 2022, honestly the gameplay footage released hasn&#x27;t really impressed. Hopefully these cinematics are their overall goal and if that were to occur, maybe Extraction will be better than it sounds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I&#x27;d love to see a e-sports setting for Siege which, while a tad ridiculous, could be great for a more casual &#x27;arcade&#x27; match format.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>All Systems Operational</title>
		<published>2020-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://otakuview.com/all-systems-operational/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://otakuview.com/all-systems-operational/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new official home of the Otaku View Community! Currently somewhat a work in progress (isn&#x27;t it obvious), this will be the hub of all our activities. This is to be a replacement of the previous Discourse forums which, while an amazing piece of software, simply went unused by our small community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our community is much more into voice chat, but at least this will tie everyone together to one place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments are also on the to-do list however for the time-being, contacting us on Discord is the best way to ask questions or provide feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How to Get the Best Deals on PC Games</title>
		<published>2020-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://otakuview.com/how-to-get-the-best-deals-on-pc-games/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://otakuview.com/how-to-get-the-best-deals-on-pc-games/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;gg-deals-homepage.png&quot; alt=&quot;gg.deals homepage&quot; title=&quot;gg.deals homepage&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a student on a limited budget, finding the best game deals is important to me and I&#x27;ve noticed many of my friends frequently surprised at what I view as fairly routine price checking. This article is meant to help you find better deals on games, however please note it is written from a PC-centric viewpoint and might not be as helpful for console or physical game deals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;alternative-storefronts&quot;&gt;Alternative Storefronts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam is an excellent source for games and hosts great deals throughout the year, but no-longer has the monopoly on the best prices it used to have.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;humble-bundle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.humblebundle.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Humble Bundle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&#x27;s somewhat-recent sale to PC Gamer has left the future quality of bundles and deals in question, there are still many solid deals to be found and they&#x27;re quite legitimate. Humble Choice (Monthly) is also a subscription service worth considering, however the overall quality of games each month can vary by taste and overall quality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;epic-games-store&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.epicgames.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;en-US&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Epic Games Store&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many strong feelings have been directed at Epic Games for creating their own storefront and launcher, however more competition in the market can only be a good thing. Frequently offering free games and deep discounts, it is an excellent source for the limited selection of games on their store and for some, the only source.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;amazon-twitch-prime&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitch.amazon.com&#x2F;tp&quot;&gt;Amazon&#x2F;Twitch Prime&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strictly speaking not a storefront, Prime does offer montly free games and other free goodies for numerous games such as League of Legends and Rocket League. While probably not worth it just for these, if you already have a subscription or want some of the other perks, it&#x27;s certainly worth taking advantage of. Be sure to check if you&#x27;re eligable for the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.com&#x2F;Amazon-Student&#x2F;&quot;&gt;student discount&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;price-comparison-sites&quot;&gt;Price Comparison Sites&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;gg-deals&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gg.deals&#x2F;&quot;&gt;gg.deals&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gg.deals is a newer deals website that searches official and grey market websites for deals on digital games. This includes support for Steam, Origin and uPlay keys and clearly designates between official retailers and less official sources. It also handily supports email notification for new deals and an import for your wishlist so you can be notified when any of your wishlist is on sale.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is certainly my first and primary choice and has replaced isthereanydeal.com for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;isthereanydeal&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;isthereanydeal.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;IsThereAnyDeal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the original price comparision websites for games, it has basically all of the features of gg.deals but with an older, less modern layout. There does appear to be a newer version in-development as well, so in the future this may be more appealing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly though, gg.deals is just plain easier to use and less confusing. Your results may vary however.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;reddit&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;gamedeals&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit has a heavily moderated list of game deals that frequently catches price errors and low-stock game sales before they vanish. If you keep a close eye, you can often get excellent deals before legit sellers run out of stock and with the heavy moderation, deals are fairly reliable. Additionally console and physical game sales are posted here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also worth checking daily, I keep a close eye here for anything that gets past my wishlist and might be flying under the radar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pre-orders&quot;&gt;Pre-orders&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I don&#x27;t encourage pre-ordering video games, but it&#x27;d be incomplete if I didn&#x27;t note that you &#x27;can&#x27; get a discount from pre-ordering. Having said that, it&#x27;s usually not worth it as the same deal can often be found within a month after release.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;time&quot;&gt;Time&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best deal of all. Most games rapidly drop in value once released and even triple-A titles are over 50% off within months of release. It&#x27;s a very simple model that assumes those who can purchase a game will do so on launch, but if you&#x27;re patient and can wait even just a month, you can usually get at least 10-20% off full retail price. There&#x27;s even a community dedicated to this on Reddit called Patient Gamers which is absolutely worth a read.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Long Dark Developer Opts-Out of GeForce Now, Faces Backlash</title>
		<published>2020-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://otakuview.com/the-long-dark-developer-geforce-now-backlash/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://otakuview.com/the-long-dark-developer-geforce-now-backlash/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;the-long-dark.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Long Dark&quot; title=&quot;The Long Dark Logo&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently Activision, Bethesda, Square Enix and now Hinterland Studio Inc, the indie developers of The Long Dark have pulled their games from GeForce Now, Nvidia&#x27;s game streaming platform alleging they never gave their permission to have their games on the platform. This seems to be following the logic that GeForce Now is the &amp;quot;Netflix&amp;quot; of games and the publishers and developers are somehow losing by having their game on an unauthorized platform. This logic simply doesn&#x27;t work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Sorry to those who are disappointed you can no longer play &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;hashtag&#x2F;thelongdark?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#thelongdark&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on GeForce Now. Nvidia didn&amp;#39;t ask for our permission to put the game on the platform so we asked them to remove it. Please take your complaints to them, not us. Devs should control where their games exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Raphael van Lierop (@RaphLife) &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;RaphLife&#x2F;status&#x2F;1234181315840229376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 1, 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;platform.twitter.com&#x2F;widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, GeForce Now isn&#x27;t a separate platform but a streaming service for games the user already owns. In order to play The Long Dark on GeForce Now, users would need to already own a purchased copy of the game on Steam to stream it on the service. Note that this is not a &#x27;separate&#x27; copy, but simply a single copy associated with their Steam account. Herein lies the problem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steam is a license-based platform where users can login on any computer using Steam and play their games. What GeForce Now is doing is allowing users to login to Steam on their remote server and play using high-powered hardware, precisely the same as switching from a laptop to a desktop or going to an internet café. This false comparison to Netflix that is being made, that somehow Nvidia is profiting off the backs of the developers hard work would only hold up if they were providing access to users who would not otherwise be able to play the game legally on their own devices.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the rational for this might be similar to Activision&#x2F;Blizzard who clearly thought they could force additional licensing costs out of Nvidia, but this does not appear to be the case here. The Long Dark is not available on Stadia where games must be purchased again to play so this isn&#x27;t a situation of customers being funneled to an alternative product. According to Raphael&#x27;s own tweets, this decision was made as he was upset Nvidia failed to ask him for permission to let his customers play their game on Nvidia&#x27;s service.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Possibly? My main issue is not being asked, and the assumption we don&amp;#39;t need to be asked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Raphael van Lierop (@RaphLife) &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;RaphLife&#x2F;status&#x2F;1234277949508947968?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;March 2, 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;platform.twitter.com&#x2F;widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, The Long Dark is being bombarded with negative reviews and Steam has, oddly, activated their brigade protection system to protect the developer. Disabling this shows that their metric is down from 91% positive to 71% positive for the past thirty days and it seems likely this number will continue to drop before it recovers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&#x27;t support brigading, I believe these reviews are indeed legitimate as many customers may have bought the game to play using GeForce Now and due to this decision, can no longer play. This anti-consumer behavior shouldn&#x27;t be condoned or supported and I&#x27;d strongly urge customers to not support Hinterland Studios Inc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the developers, Hopefully they just deeply misunderstand what GeForce Now actually is. If they reevaluate their position and remember their customers are the only ones suffering, I&#x27;m sure the company will recover, but right now it doesn&#x27;t look so good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Bloodstained cancels Roguelike Kickstarter stretch goal</title>
		<published>2020-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://otakuview.com/bloodstained-cancels-roguelike-kickstarter-stretchgoal/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://otakuview.com/bloodstained-cancels-roguelike-kickstarter-stretchgoal/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;bloodstained-gameplay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bloodstained Gameplay&quot; title=&quot;Bloodstained Gameplay&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;store.steampowered.com&#x2F;app&#x2F;692850&#x2F;Bloodstained_Ritual_of_the_Night&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bloodstained: Ritual of the Night&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Koji Igarashi is a critically reviewed Castlevania-style RPG that released on Steam in June of 2019 after a very successful &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.kickstarter.com&#x2F;projects&#x2F;iga&#x2F;bloodstained-ritual-of-the-night&#x2F;description&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; back in 2015. &lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;With a goal of $500,000, they managed to blow past that within twenty-four hours and reached an impressive $5,545,991 of pledges, in part due to the allure of their additional stretch goals. One of these, the five million dollar mark, was for a Roguelike Dungeon which, as noted in the title, has been cancelled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most notable about this is that the game has been Overwhelmingly Positive on Steam since release, however after news of this cancelation was announced it has been peppered with negative reviews accusing the developers of being liars and scammers. While I don&#x27;t believe the developers intentionally lied, the argument they make for being unable to deliver a Roguelike system shows they knew, or should have known, long ago that such an addition was impossible to attain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Unfortunately, the code that was created early in the game’s development is not currently compatible with this type of gameplay (especially a procedurally generated castle).&amp;quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.kickstarter.com&#x2F;projects&#x2F;iga&#x2F;bloodstained-ritual-of-the-night&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2772919&quot;&gt;Jason Ryan, Senior Community Manager - 505 Games&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This excuse indicates at best, poor project management and, as many have accused, at worst, a deliberate attempt to mislead customers to obtain their support. Personally I&#x27;m more prone to believe it was simply poor management, especially with their addition of a randomizer game mode to attempt to &amp;quot;fill the gap&amp;quot;, but even so I can sympathize with the frustration of many gamers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kind of changes are happening more and more often with Kickstarter and Early Access games and the many bad actors in the market are eroding the trust gamers have in these marketplaces. While this may be a case of simply poor management, it&#x27;s difficult to discern for certain and with this becoming more and more common, I&#x27;m worried gamers will stop caring whether these issues occur intentionally and just start attacking developers for every last change they make.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
